<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on s9a.me</title><link>https://s9a.me/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on s9a.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 09:23:11 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://s9a.me/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekly Unix #6 - job control (2)</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-19-weekly-unix-6-job-control-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-19-weekly-unix-6-job-control-2/</guid><description>Finer Job Selection In the previous article we saw basics of job control but we skipped alternatives to select jobs. Consider the following job listing throughout this article.
$jobs [1] Running find . -name *.xml &amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp; [2]- Stopped cat /dev/zero &amp;gt; /dev/null [3]+ Stopped find . -name *.cc &amp;gt; /dev/null 1. Using job number You can use the job number (the number in square bracket) to work on it.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Unix #6 - job control</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-18-weekly-unix-6-job-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-18-weekly-unix-6-job-control/</guid><description>Some commands take long time to finish execution. For example if you are searching for a file in a directory or extracting/compressing a directory or maybe building a project which take quite some time to complete. The command when executed takes a while to complete and thereby occupy the terminal preventing you from doing other stuff.
Linux (since a multitasking operating system) offers neat job control tools to deal with this.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Unix #5 - cd</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-17-cd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-17-cd/</guid><description>man cd No manual entry for cd That’s because there isn’t any! cd is an internal shell command.
So where do I find help? Well there isn’t much in cd that you can do except change the directory. But since this operation is done hundreds of times a day, we need to do it efficiently.
cd - cd with a hyphen goes to previous directory and executing that again comes back to current directory.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Unix #4 - ls</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-15-ls-list-directory-contents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-15-ls-list-directory-contents/</guid><description>This command is one of the most widely used (no references, just guessing) command. It simple lists the directory contents. It lists files, directories and links in current directory (default behavior). The command and it’s variants are so widely used, that some of the distributions contains some aliases for this command in the .bashrc file. For example I am using Mint and it already contains these ls aliases in my .</description></item><item><title>CDPATH: The lesser known path variable</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-13-cdpath/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-13-cdpath/</guid><description>CDPATH is an environment variable under UNIX, which is referred every time cd command is invoked.
The working of cd Let’s say you invoke the following command:
cd blog The directory blog is looked in current working directory. If found, the current working directory is changed to that. If it is not found there, it is looked in every path in the CDPATH variable. Again if found, it is changed. If not then a directory not found message is displayed and cd returns 1 (Error code).</description></item><item><title>Weekly Unix #3 - tee</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-03-unix-command-tee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/linux/2016-07-03-unix-command-tee/</guid><description>tee command as the man page puts it, reads from standard input and writes to standard output and files. Okay good enough but what does that mean? Well that mean, while using a command, the output is sent to the console. You can redirect it to file by using &amp;gt; and &amp;gt;&amp;gt; to a file. That symbol is of output redirection (a summary of that in the end of this post and all the output redirection is covered in separate post).</description></item></channel></rss>