<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on s9a.me</title><link>https://s9a.me/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on s9a.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://s9a.me/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Proxy Interfaces In Java</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-12-13-proxy-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-12-13-proxy-interfaces/</guid><description>Java provides a static method Proxy.newProxyInstance as part of it&amp;rsquo;s Reflection API. This static method returns a proxy class for a given set of interfaces. It requires only 3 things:
A class loader A list of interfaces that this proxy should implement An InvacationHandler. This is like a callback which is invoked when methods on this proxy are called. Proxy Class Properties The proxy classes are public, final and non-abstract This proxy classes extend java.</description></item><item><title>Creating TestContainers from Dockerfile and DSL</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-07-test-containers-from-dockerfile-and-dsl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-07-test-containers-from-dockerfile-and-dsl/</guid><description>Containers make the job of writing integration test cases quite easy which rely on a tool like a database or cloud infrastructure or any other tool for that matter. Test containers take it a step further but letting us create containers from the code itself.
There is another neat trick in TestContainers that let’s us create the containers on the fly. From Dockerfile or directly by declaring the container spec with Java using a DSL.</description></item><item><title>Side Effect Free Functions</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-04-side-effect-free-functions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-04-side-effect-free-functions/</guid><description>While writing code, we call various functions. Broadly, these can be divided into two categorized - commands and queries.
Queries often query the database, state of the system or return value of a variable. Commands on the other hand modify the state of the system. For example by changing a variable.
What is a side effect What is side effect? Most function calls call other function who in term call other set of functions.</description></item><item><title>Using a Separate Source Root for Integration Tests</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/java/2022-12-31-using-separate-source-root-for-integration-tests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/java/2022-12-31-using-separate-source-root-for-integration-tests/</guid><description>In Java if we apply the java plugin we get two source roots - main and test to write our main code and all our tests. It&amp;rsquo;s often useful to have a separate directory for integration tests instead of using some sort of tagging or file naming convention to run those different suites.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do that!
First, create the directory To start with, create a new directory called integration under src directory.</description></item><item><title>Safely Rolling Out Features Using Feature Flags</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-28-releasing-safely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-28-releasing-safely/</guid><description>In this article we will walk through steps to rollout an upgrade as safely as possible.
What you will need A feature controller A configuration for the feature Infrastructure to deploy canary releases (optional; if you like to play with fire without wearing gloves) Safely Rolling Out Change Create a feature in feature controller for the new feature with default value set to disabled. Write code for the new feature but behind this new condition using the feature controller.</description></item><item><title>Fundamental Join Algorithms and IO Cost</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/databases/2022-12-24-fundamental-join-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/databases/2022-12-24-fundamental-join-algorithms/</guid><description>Joins are integral part of relational databases and they are designed to do them well.
There are few considerations before we join two table which can make a lot of difference on the performance of the query - whether there is an index present, what are the sizes of table? Can one table be fit in memory or whether an external disk sort could be required to perform the join efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Types of Indexes</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/databases/type-of-indexes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/databases/type-of-indexes/</guid><description>Database indexes may make or break your query. Learn about various kinds of indexes in this post and when they are best suited.
Indexes can be broadly categorized in two categories - sorted and hash based. Sorted are generally backed by tree based data structure and support range queries (salary &amp;gt; 10,000) whereas hash indexes are like hash maps, best suited for lookups (salary = 10,000).
flowchart TB A[Indices] --&amp;gt; B[Sorted Indices] A --&amp;gt; C[Hash Based Indices] Ordered Indices An Ordered Index stores values in sorted order like phone numbers in a directory or index of a book.</description></item><item><title>A brief summary of Google's Monorepo</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-21-about-googles-mono-repo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-21-about-googles-mono-repo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll first talk about the code repo and how Goole makes it work, followed by the pros and cons and in the end whether it&amp;rsquo;s needed today.
About Most of the code in Google is written in a single repository - taking mono repos to the another level. This article is a summary of another paper title Why Google stores billions of lines of code in a single repository published by Rachel Potvin.</description></item><item><title>Vagrant - Setting up and tearing down development environments on the fly</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-07-02-vagrant-setting-up-and-tearing-down-development-environments-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-07-02-vagrant-setting-up-and-tearing-down-development-environments-on-the-fly/</guid><description>I try a lot of new things and this trying new things forces me to install something new. I hate installing new packages/frameworks just because I want to try it. Nothing is removed cleanly later and your OS is left with configuration files, user files, hidden directories and lot more trash created by this new package. I hate that!
Up till now, I had no option. I used to install, then remove and after a while lot of unwanted files would be lying here and there.</description></item></channel></rss>