<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes Page on s9a.me</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Notes Page on s9a.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://s9a.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Idea Rule In Writing</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2024-01-06-one-idea-rule-while-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2024-01-06-one-idea-rule-while-writing/</guid><description>Write.</description></item><item><title>Proxy Interfaces In Java</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-12-13-proxy-interfaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-12-13-proxy-interfaces/</guid><description>Java provides a static method Proxy.newProxyInstance as part of it&amp;rsquo;s Reflection API. This static method returns a proxy class for a given set of interfaces. It requires only 3 things:
A class loader A list of interfaces that this proxy should implement An InvacationHandler. This is like a callback which is invoked when methods on this proxy are called. Proxy Class Properties The proxy classes are public, final and non-abstract This proxy classes extend java.</description></item><item><title>Dendron is neat alternative to note taking</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-04-15-dendron/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-04-15-dendron/</guid><description>I generally use Notion to keep my notes and journal but for office work, it&amp;rsquo;s not a good idea to publish these notes to a third party application.
My second preferred way is open Visual Studio Code on a directory and start writing there. Group by projects, track the work with various extensions. But I needed a better tool to link the notes, tag them, categorize them - meeting notes, journal, ideas, etc.</description></item><item><title>Spotless - an alternative to Checkstyle that applies the formatting</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-15-spotless-checkstyle-alternative-apply-formatting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-15-spotless-checkstyle-alternative-apply-formatting/</guid><description>Checkstyle is a wonderful tool when we want to enforce the style guidelines in the project. But it has 2 major problems:
It can&amp;rsquo;t apply the formatting, it can only check whether the code is compatable. You need to rely on alternatives like suggested in this Stack Overflow thread. But there is no programattic way to do it. It can&amp;rsquo;t work only on the changes that you have made. For you to only check with the files that you have modified, you need a workaround suggested in this article.</description></item><item><title>Car Pool For Housing Societies and Offices</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-11-car-pool-for-housing-societies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-11-car-pool-for-housing-societies/</guid><description>I quite often see posts on WhatsApp group asking people if they are going certain direction, either to drop something or someone. Offices typically see people pooling together. But there is a limitation with discovering people like this because you are restricted to the WhatsApp groups you are part of or the people you know. There is also any psychological barrier to ask such questions or post every day morning that I’m going to office and people can tag along.</description></item><item><title>Creating TestContainers from Dockerfile and DSL</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-07-test-containers-from-dockerfile-and-dsl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-07-test-containers-from-dockerfile-and-dsl/</guid><description>Containers make the job of writing integration test cases quite easy which rely on a tool like a database or cloud infrastructure or any other tool for that matter. Test containers take it a step further but letting us create containers from the code itself.
There is another neat trick in TestContainers that let’s us create the containers on the fly. From Dockerfile or directly by declaring the container spec with Java using a DSL.</description></item><item><title>Side Effect Free Functions</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-04-side-effect-free-functions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2023-01-04-side-effect-free-functions/</guid><description>While writing code, we call various functions. Broadly, these can be divided into two categorized - commands and queries.
Queries often query the database, state of the system or return value of a variable. Commands on the other hand modify the state of the system. For example by changing a variable.
What is a side effect What is side effect? Most function calls call other function who in term call other set of functions.</description></item><item><title>Safely Rolling Out Features Using Feature Flags</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-28-releasing-safely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-28-releasing-safely/</guid><description>In this article we will walk through steps to rollout an upgrade as safely as possible.
What you will need A feature controller A configuration for the feature Infrastructure to deploy canary releases (optional; if you like to play with fire without wearing gloves) Safely Rolling Out Change Create a feature in feature controller for the new feature with default value set to disabled. Write code for the new feature but behind this new condition using the feature controller.</description></item><item><title>A brief summary of Google's Monorepo</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-21-about-googles-mono-repo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-21-about-googles-mono-repo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll first talk about the code repo and how Goole makes it work, followed by the pros and cons and in the end whether it&amp;rsquo;s needed today.
About Most of the code in Google is written in a single repository - taking mono repos to the another level. This article is a summary of another paper title Why Google stores billions of lines of code in a single repository published by Rachel Potvin.</description></item><item><title>Create a service mocking framework around Proxy.newProxyInstance</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-17-proxy-new-instance-json-mock-utility/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-17-proxy-new-instance-json-mock-utility/</guid><description>Introducing Proxy.newProxyInstance The Java Reflection API provides a helper method to create proxy implementation (substitute or placeholder for another object[1]) of any class.
The idea is to provide a list of classes or interfaces that this new proxy would inherit/implement and provide a callback which will be invoked every time the proxy is called.
Code Example With this knowledge and the documentation, let’s see if this in action and understand more from there.</description></item><item><title>Network Namespaces and Veth pairs</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-14-network-namespaces-and-veth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2022-12-14-network-namespaces-and-veth/</guid><description>Containers are a thing now and microservices the new buzz word. But how do containers work? How are containers magically separated from each other?
VMs require an entire operating system running and therefore consumes memory and CPU. In fact, if I remember correctly, running a Ubuntu VM requires atleast 500-600mb of memory and at least one CPU core. But containers run in fraction of resources and provide almost similar features for an application developer.</description></item><item><title>Design Patterns for Container Based Distributed Systems</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2021-11-30-design-patterns-for-container-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2021-11-30-design-patterns-for-container-application/</guid><description>This article is inspired from paper titled with the same name published by Brendan Burns and David Oppenheimer
Containers now a days are becoming more and more analogous to objects in object-oriented programming. Like objects, containers should be small and should do one and only one thing. That’s just another way of saying Single Responsibility Principle. We are seeing a similar trend from the late 1980s and early 1990s when object-oriented programming revolutionized software development.</description></item><item><title>Why you should not use null as a method parameter</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2020-01-06-design-oop-avoid-using-nulls-method-argument/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2020-01-06-design-oop-avoid-using-nulls-method-argument/</guid><description>Object Oriented concept was first introduced with Lisp in the late 1950s. Lisp has atoms and attributes, where the atoms represented an real world object. OOP has evolved quite a bit after that. SOLID design principle were introduced that helped us craft a better software. I will not go in details of how these principles help us, there is already lot of material out there. Instead I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on some mistakes we do while implementing these patterns.</description></item><item><title>Insert, Index document in Elasticsearch using Java</title><link>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/insert-index-document-elasticsearch-java/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/insert-index-document-elasticsearch-java/</guid><description>In this article we will see how to insert a document in Elasticsearch using the High Level Client provided by Elasticsearch.
Prepare the Index Request Elasticsearch client accepts IndexRequest to insert documents. Two required details for this request are:
Name of the index Document source Everything else can take default value. We will stick to the easy path to create our very first document and explore other optional arguments later.</description></item><item><title>Search Elasticsearch from Java using High Level Client</title><link>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/search-match-all-from-java-using-high-level-client/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/search-match-all-from-java-using-high-level-client/</guid><description>In [the last post]({% post_url elasticsearch/2019-11-25-connecting-to-elasticsearch-from-java %}) we saw how to connect to Elasticsearch using the High Level Client.
match_all Query using Java client The client provides many high level methods to build an Elasticsearch query. To keep it simple, let&amp;rsquo;s see how to construct a simple match_all query:
SearchRequest request = new SearchRequest(&amp;#34;online&amp;#34;); // -- 1 SearchSourceBuilder builder = new SearchSourceBuilder(); // -- 2 builder.query(QueryBuilders.matchAllQuery()); request.source(builder); // -- 3 Parameter to the constructor is the index you want to query, this can be left empty and all the indices will be queried SearchSourceBuilder is used to create a search request.</description></item><item><title>Connect to Elasticsearch using Java High Level Client</title><link>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/connect-from-java-using-high-level-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/elasticsearch/connect-from-java-using-high-level-client/</guid><description>Elasticsearch provides a client to conveniently connect with Elasticsearch. Create a Maven project and add the following maven dependency:
Add Maven Dependency &amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.elasticsearch.client&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;elasticsearch-rest-high-level-client&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;7.3.1&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; Set Up connection with Elasticsearch Elasticsearch maintains 2 clients - Low Level Client and High Level Client. It is recommended to use the High Level Client to query and index documents in Elasticsearch. You can create connection to Elasticsearch like this:
RestHighLevelClient client = new RestHighLevelClient( RestClient.</description></item><item><title>Create your first Docker container</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2019-09-28-creating-your-first-docker-image/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2019-09-28-creating-your-first-docker-image/</guid><description>Part 1 of a multi-part essay on configuring Docker in production.
Prerequisites You have Docker installed (See instructions to install) (Optional) You know to to deploy a Flask application using command line Docker works on basis of configurations. It&amp;rsquo;s a declarative way of telling Docker how to build images.
A typical workflow starts with a base image, works on top of it, saves it either for future use or gets reused as a base image of something else.</description></item><item><title>Pandas: Splitting (Exploding) a column into multiple rows</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-11-21-pandas-splitting-exploding-string-column-into-multiple-rows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-11-21-pandas-splitting-exploding-string-column-into-multiple-rows/</guid><description>Recently, while working with on something in my office, I faced a small but interesting problem. I had to clean some data and the data was not normalized. In one of the columns, a single cell had multiple comma seperated values. I could not find out the distribution of how frequently the value was appearing without splitting these cells into individual cells of their own; creating new rows.
Example:
# Input data: EmployeeId, City 001, Mumbai|Bangalore 002, Pune|Mumbai|Delhi 003, Mumbai|Bangalore 004, Mumbai|Pune 005, Bangalore .</description></item><item><title>On The Turing Test</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-08-04-the-turing-test/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-08-04-the-turing-test/</guid><description>The Imitation Game or Turing Test has become the hallmark of the question - ‘Can machines think?’. Turing predicts that by the end of 20th century, machine would be able to think. Humans have been on moon after that and machines are still at the dawn of thinking. Thinking. The paper is philosophical one and ‘think’ is a vague term which cannot be determined in simple yes or no. Turing has therefore, given a method, a test through which we can assess if machines can think.</description></item><item><title>Running in Pig in Local Mode in Java</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-08-01-running-hadoop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 07:11:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-08-01-running-hadoop/</guid><description>Overview of steps Create a new maven project Add Hadoop and Pig dependencies Write a small pig script to count words in a file Write a driver program that will run this pig script 1. Create a new maven project mvn archetype:generate -DgroupId=com.example -DartifactId=piglocal -DarchetypeArtifactId=maven-archetype-webapp -DinteractiveMode=false You can now import the project in your IDE.
2. Add Hadoop and Pig dependencies Pig needs the following dependencies:
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.pig&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;pig&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.17.0&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;log4j&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;log4j&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;1.</description></item><item><title>Running Spark Locally</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-01-30-running-spark-locally/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2018-01-30-running-spark-locally/</guid><description>Running distributed applications on local machine might seem like a tedious task, but apparently it’s pretty easy.
1. Download and extract the binary The binary can be downloaded from here, extract it somewhere, let’s call it SPARK_HOME
2. Running the master cd $SPARK_HOME/sbin ./start-master.sh Verify permissions if you are not able to run it
The script will emit some log statement and a URL where master is running. On local machine this will be of format: spark://your-machine-name:7077</description></item><item><title>Boilerplate - Logging in Python</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-08-03-boilerplate-for-logging-in-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-08-03-boilerplate-for-logging-in-python/</guid><description>This is how all my Python scripts look like when they start:
import logging logging.basicConfig(level=logging.DEBUG) logger = logging.getLogger(__name__) logger.debug(&amp;#39;Log message&amp;#39;) Nothing much but I prefer logging over print statements. Whenever I want to move this small script to larger project, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to make lot of changes. Logging also offers more control over the messages and what messages to print or skip.</description></item><item><title>Vagrant - Setting up and tearing down development environments on the fly</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-07-02-vagrant-setting-up-and-tearing-down-development-environments-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2017-07-02-vagrant-setting-up-and-tearing-down-development-environments-on-the-fly/</guid><description>I try a lot of new things and this trying new things forces me to install something new. I hate installing new packages/frameworks just because I want to try it. Nothing is removed cleanly later and your OS is left with configuration files, user files, hidden directories and lot more trash created by this new package. I hate that!
Up till now, I had no option. I used to install, then remove and after a while lot of unwanted files would be lying here and there.</description></item><item><title>Elasticsearch Bulk API Example and Performance Comparison</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/elasticsearch/2017-04-14-elasticsearch-bulk-api-example-and-performance-comparison/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 10:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/elasticsearch/2017-04-14-elasticsearch-bulk-api-example-and-performance-comparison/</guid><description>Elasticsearch provides bulk operations to perform multiple operations in a single call. Bulk APIs can be accessed by hitting the _bulk endpoint. This post demonstrates the use of bulk API with Python. It assumes that you are familiar (not expert) with REST Bulk API of Elasticsearch. To keep it simple we will just consider the insertion case.
Problem Statement Before we jump into code, let’s take a minute and think about the problem in hand.</description></item><item><title>Memento</title><link>https://s9a.me/posts/2016-08-11-memento/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://s9a.me/posts/2016-08-11-memento/</guid><description>Ever used an image editing software? We opened an image but it’s too sharp and the light is not good. We make some changes and still not satisfied, we make few more changes only to realize that the previous changes were better than these new! We want to restore to previous changes. If we were using a drawing sheet and paint brush, this task would be very difficult; perhaps impossible. But with softwares, that’s not a problem.</description></item></channel></rss>