<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Competitive Coding on suresh sarda</title><link>/notes/competitive-coding/</link><description>Recent content in Competitive Coding on suresh sarda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/notes/competitive-coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solution to Leetcode - Happy Number</title><link>/problem-solving/leetcode/solution-happy-number/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/problem-solving/leetcode/solution-happy-number/</guid><description>As part of 30 days challenge during the Corono pandemic, Leetcode published this problem on the second day:
A happy number is a number defined by the following process: Starting with any positive integer, replace the number by the sum of the squares of its digits, and repeat the process until the number equals 1 (where it will stay), or it loops endlessly in a cycle which does not include 1.</description></item><item><title>Hackerrank - maximum-draw solution</title><link>/notes/competitive-coding/2016-06-10-hackerrank-maximum-draw-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/competitive-coding/2016-06-10-hackerrank-maximum-draw-solution/</guid><description>Solution to HackerRank question: maximum draw
Explanation This one is really simple. The question is:
Jim is off to a party and is searching for a matching pair of socks. His drawer is filled with socks, each pair of a different color. In its worst case scenario, how many socks (x) should Jim remove from his drawer until he finds a matching pair?
So Jim keeps removing socks from drawer, and the moment he finds a pair(repeat color) he stops.</description></item><item><title>Hackerrank - find-point solution</title><link>/notes/competitive-coding/2016-06-05-hackerrank-find-point-solution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/notes/competitive-coding/2016-06-05-hackerrank-find-point-solution/</guid><description>Solution to HackerRank FindPoint
Domain Knowledge Required What is a symmetric point? Given 2 points P and Q, a symmetric point of P against Q is such that Q is the midpoint of the line joining P and the symmetric point P’. In other words, let’s say a point P’ is the symmetric point. Then,
P-Q-P’are on one line Dist(PQ) = Dist(QP’) Code import java.io.*; import java.util.*; import java.</description></item></channel></rss>